《老友记》前情提要
Previously on Friends...
我觉得自己好像根本没有女朋友
I don't feel like I have a girlfriend any more.
你是不是要我辞职
You want me to quit my job so
好让你觉得自己有女朋友
you can feel like you got a girlfriend?
-这是因为马克吗  -我的天
- Is this about Mark? - Oh, my God.
-好  不是  -我的老天爷
- Okay, it's not. - Oh, my God.
我不能总跟你为同一件事吵架  罗斯
I cannot keep having the same fight with you, Ross!
也许我们应该分开一下
Look, maybe we should just take a break.
很好  你说得对  我们冷静一下
Fine. You're right. Let's take a break.
我们去吃冻酸奶吧
Let's get some frozen yogurt or something.
不  我们分开吧
No. A break from us.
然后我们大吵了一架
Then we had this big stupid fight,
我说我想分开
and I said I wanted to take a break.
我不想分开
I don't want to take a break.
我在想这太荒唐了
I've been thinking, this is crazy.
你不觉得我们可以再沟通吗
Don't you think we can work on this?
你想喝什么
What do you want to drink?
那是谁
Who's that?
没有人
Nobody.
是马克吗
Is that Mark?
亲爱的  他只是过来
Honey, look, he just...
好  我懂了
Yeah. Got it!
来跳舞吧  怎么  你结婚了吗
Hey, come dance. What,  are you married?
因为这也无所谓
Because that's okay.
昨晚的周年纪念日大餐怎么样
How was the big anniversary dinner?
我们根本没机会吃晚餐
Well, we never actually got to dinner.
很好
Nice.
我们分手了
No, we kind of broke up instead.
什么
What?
我的天  莫妮卡  喷到天花板了
My God, Monica! It's on the ceiling!
没关系
That's okay.
这件事的重要性超过水果
This is more important than fruit...
在我的天花板上
on my ceiling.
你们分手了
You broke up?
对  不过没关系
Yeah,  but it's okay,
罗斯走后  马克来了
because when Ross left,  Mark came over.
不会吧  瑞秋  你跟马克
Oh, no! Rachel, you and Mark?
没事  冷静
No, it's okay. Calm down.
马克跟我聊了聊
Mark and I talked...
我意识到自己有多爱你的蠢大哥
and I realized how much I love your stupid brother.
我们是有问题  但我真心想跟他继续下去
We got our problems,  but I really wanna make it work.
早安
Morning!
是我  我找了你一整夜  我好难过
Hi, it's me. I've been trying to reach you all night. I feel awful.
请相信我  罗斯  我跟马克没有什么
Please, Ross, you've gotta know there's nothing between me and Mark.
-我们分手这事真是太傻了  -没错
- This whole breakup thing is just stupid. - Yeah.
我这样折磨你  真对不起
I'm just so sorry I put you through it.
我不想用答录机和好
And I don't want to get back together over a machine.
我爱你
So I love you.
I love you.
跟你说  我要睡了
And you know what? I'm gonna go to bed now...
但我明早上班时会过来
but on my way to work tomorrow morning,
八点半左右  再见
I'm gonna stop by around 8:30. Bye.
克萝伊  你好了没有
Chloe, how's it coming?
你觉得我应该买什么样的狗
What kind of puppy do you think I should get?
不知道  买只大狗怎么样
Well, I don't know, how about a big one?
-可是我的公寓  -那买小狗好了
- But my apartment's so... - Then a small one.
听着  我们该走了
Listen, let's... We have to go.
等等  我的鞋子呢
Wait! Where's my shoes?
你要穿鞋子
You need shoes?
我们干嘛这么赶
Do I know why we're rushing?
我昨晚跟你说了我的女朋友
Yeah, you know the girlfriend I told you about last night?
现在她又想跟我和好了
It turns out that she wants to get back together with me.
找到了
I found it!
那真是太好了
That's so great for you guys!
你一定很高兴
You must be so happy!
对  高兴  但我同时也百感交集
Yes, I am. One of the many things I'm feeling.
-祝你们好运  -谢谢
- Good luck with your girlfriend. - Thank you.
瑞秋
Rachel.
-你听到我的留言没有  -你真准时
- You got my message? - You are right on time!
怎么样
So, what do you say?
我可以再做你的女朋友吗
Can I be your girlfriend again?
当然可以  这样最好了
Yes, you can. Very much.
-你干嘛拖天花板  -上面有香蕉
- Why are you mopping your ceiling? - There's banana on it.
我家住着个印第安老女人的灵魂
I have the spirit of an old Indian woman living in mine.
所以  你知道
So, then, you know.
邮差来过了  我帮你把信拿上来了
The mailman was down downstairs, so I brought your mail.
-很好  谢谢  -法布科技是什么
- Oh, good. Thanks. - Now, what is Fabutech?
别鄙视我  好吗
Okay, don't judge me too much, okay?
我看到一个购物广告  我发誓我从来没有
I saw this infomercial, and I swear to you I have never, ever...
买过购物频道的东西
bought anything on TV before.
除了这个拖把
Except for this mop.
不过这个腿部脱毛膏  看起来好棒
But there was this stuff on leg-waxing. It looked so amazing.
"超脱"脱毛膏
Waxine!
对  你看过吗
Yes! Have you seen it?
太棒了  我早就想当"超脱"女郎了
It's incredible! I so want to be a Waxine Girl!
我知道
I know!
你觉得真的不会痛吗  什么原理啊
God, do you think it really doesn't hurt? How can they do that?
是最近才在雨林深处
Hello! Organic substances recently discovered
发现的有机物质哟
in the depths of the rain forest?
那里可都是日月之精华
They have the best stuff in there.
我的天
Oh, my God!
我们当时找不到你
We figured when we couldn't find you,
还以为你去跟瑞秋和好了
you'd gone home to make up with Rachel.
你当时应该那样做才对
Which is probably what you should have done.
你说呢
You think?
老天  我完蛋了  我该怎么办
God, I'm in hell. I mean, what am I gonna do?
瑞秋一直说"我爱你"
Rachel's all like "I love you",
"我们要解决问题"
and "Let's work on this"...
而我满脑子都是
and all I can think about...
如果我把实情告诉她
is what is she gonna do what she gonna say
她会怎么做怎么说
when I tell her what I did?
问答这个之前
Before we answer that,
我们应该谈比较重要的问题
I think we should address the more important question:
你到底有多蠢
how dumb are you?
怎么了
What?
我们努力想修复这份感情  好吗
Look, we're trying to rebuild a relationship here, right?
如果不诚实
How am I supposed to do that without
还谈什么感情
being totally honest with each other?
罗斯  我也赞成要坦诚  真的
Ross, look. I'm onboard about the total-honesty thing. I am.
不过会惹麻烦的事  还是少说为妙
Just not about stuff that's gonna get you in trouble.
他说得对  这对谁都没好处
He's right. Nobody's gonna benefit,
你只会伤害她
and you'll just hurt her.
到时候连感情都没了 还修复什么呢
And there won't be a relationship left to rebuild.
对  可你不觉得
Yeah, but don't you think...
如果你真的要非说不可
All right look, if you absolutely have to tell her,
至少要等到适当的时机
at least wait till the timing's right.
所以临终之前才要忏悔
And that's what deathbeds are for.
-好吧  -很好
- Yeah, okay. - All right.
好了  我们必须确定
Okay. Now, we just have to make sure
她不会从其它的渠道知道
she doesn't find out some other way.
你有没有想到关联
Did you think about the trail?
什么关联
What trail?
从你勾搭的那个女人开始一路循迹
The trail from the woman you did it with...
直到你千方百计要隐瞒的女人
to the woman you hope never finds out you did it!
永远不要忘了关联
You always have to think about the trail!
我想应该没有什么关联吧
I don't think there's any trail.
好了好了
Okay, okay...
克萝伊的同事艾塞克
Chloe works with that guy, Isaac.
艾塞克的妹妹洁丝敏
Isaac's sister is Jasmine,
是菲比在按摩中心的同事
and Jasmine works at the massage place with Phoebe.
菲比是瑞秋的朋友
And Phoebe's friends with Rachel,
这就是关联  我找到了
and that's the trail! I did it!
敷上"超脱"脱毛膏  把布条贴在腿上
"After applying the Waxine and linen strips to leg number one"
好了
Did that!
抓住布条的易撕端
"Grasp one of the linen strips by its easy-grab tab...
快速扯下来  完全无痛
and pull it off in one quick, pain-free motion."
好的
Okay.
这不是无痛的吗
Was it not "pain-free"?
不  痛死了
No, it was pain-ful!
我的天  这应该叫超痛脱一点点毛膏
My God, they should call it "Pain-zine, now with a little wax."
广告上穿缎子睡衣的女孩们
Well, the girls in the satin nighties on the commercial...
好像不觉得有这么痛
don't seem to think it's that bad.
那是因为她们太笨
That's because their nerves are probably deadened
所以神经都很大条
from being so stupid.
如果你不相信我的话  尽管自己试试看
But you know, if you don't believe me, please, be my guest.
我的妈呀
Oh, my God!
这下你该庆幸我们没贴比基尼条了吧
Now are you glad we didn't start with the bikini strips?
克萝伊  嗨
Chloe, hi.
是因为我拿走你的手表吗
Is this about me taking your watch?
你拿了我的手表
You took my watch?
对不起  我有这种习惯
I'm sorry. I do that.
你留着吧
You keep it.
听我说  你把我们的事跟别人说了吗
Listen, did you tell anyone about us?
没有  我觉得不关别人的事
Oh, no, I feel like it really isn't anybody's business. You know?
没错  那你也没有告诉艾塞克吧
Exactly. So you didn't mention anything to Isaac right?
我什么事都告诉艾塞克
I tell Isaac everything.
真的  那当然啦
You do? Of course you do.
嗨  艾塞克  艾塞克  你好
Hi, Isaac. Isaac, hi.
我们还没有正式见过面
You know, we haven't actually met.
你个色狗
You dog!
对  我想我是狗
Yes, I suppose I am a dog.
不过艾塞克  我有个女朋友
But Issac, see I-I happen to have a girlfriend.
对  咖啡馆的瑞秋
Oh, right, that Rachel chick from the coffee place.
就是她  我不想伤害她
That's the one. Listen, I don't want to hurt her.
我知道  不管我们有多爱她们
Oh, hey, man, I know. It doesn't matter how much we love them.
一夫一妻制真是太没有天理了
Monogamy is too cruel a rule.
听我说  可以请你保守这个秘密吗
Listen, can you keep this information to yourself?
没问题  我们要互相关照才行
No problem dude. We gotta look out for each other.
咱们是一样的  你跟我
We're the same, you and me.
其实  不  我们不一样
Actually, no, we're not.
没错  一样的
Yeah, we are.
不  不一样
No, we're not.
一样
Yeah, we are.
不一样
No, we're not.
-好  不一样  -这才对
- Okay, we're not. - Right.
不过我们是一样的
But we are.
好  我只想知道你不会告诉你妹妹
Fine. I just need to know that you're not gonna tell your sister.
我可以保证不会再跟她说
I can promise not to tell her again.
洁丝敏  我们在菲比的生日派对见过
Jasmine? We met at Phoebe's birthday party.
我是罗斯·盖勒
I'm Ross Geller.
你做了一件坏事
You did a bad thing!
-没错  -非常坏
- Yes, I did. - Very bad!
-非常坏  -非常非常坏
- Very bad. - Very very bad!
我完全同意你的话
I'm agreeing with you.
听我说  你告诉菲比没有
Listen, did you happen to tell Phoebe yet?
没
No.
好  洁丝敏  拜托你  不要说
Ok. Jasmine, Please. Please don't.
我很爱我的女朋友
I love my girlfriend very much
我无比希望能跟她继续交往  明白吗
and I want more than anything to just work it out with her. Okay?
好吧
All right.
谢谢你  谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
不过你应该去找我的室友
But you should probably talk to my roommate.
我跟他说了  他也认识菲比
Because I told him, and he knows Phoebe too.
你的室友是谁
Who's your roommate?
甘瑟
Gunther!
甘瑟  请告诉我你没有告诉瑞秋
Gunther, please tell me you didn't say anything to Rachel
我跟影印店那个女孩的事
about me and the girl from the copy place.
对不起
I'm sorry.
难道我不该说吗
Was I not supposed to?
-我们没事  -没事  没事
- We're all right. - It's okay. It's okay.
-我们只是在去腿毛  -把腿去掉吗
- We were just waxing our legs. - Off?
告诉你们
For your information,
男人永远不会经历这种痛苦
this happens to be a pain like no man will ever experience.
你最好不要说这种话
Yeah, well I don't think you can make that statement,
除非你的重要部位
unless you've been kicked in an area
曾经被狠狠踢过
that God only meant to be treated nicely.
对  我觉得只不过是女人的
Yeah, I-I think that women just have a
痛感极限比男人低罢了
lower threshold for pain than men, that's all.
拜托  只不过是一点脱毛膏而已
I mean, come on, it's just a little wax.
是吗  过来
Oh, yeah? Come here.
你太幼稚了
Oh, that's mature.
好的  现在撕掉就好了吗
Okay, fine. So now I just pull it off?
没错
That's right.
瑞秋  拜托跟我谈谈  求你了
Rachel, come on. Talk to me. Please!
跟你谈  我连看都不想看你一眼
Talk to you? I can't even look at you right now.
怎么了
What?
没事  没事
Nothing. Nothing.
-她刚还说没事了  -他们在说什么呢
- She said everything was okay. - What are they talking about?
瑞秋
Rachel.
你滚远一点
Just get away from me!
那是个错误  我犯了个错  好吗
It was a mistake, I made a mistake, okay?
犯错  你之前是想放进哪里
A mistake? What were you trying to put it in?
她包里吗
Her purse?
他放进哪里了
Where did he put it?
罗斯  你跟另外一个女人上了床
Ross, you had sex with another woman!
我的天
Oh, my God!
我早就知道有事
I knew something had to be wrong,
我的指甲昨天一点都没长
because my fingernails didn't grow at all yesterday.
我想是他们吵了一架  他喝醉了
Yeah, well, I guess they had a fight, and he got drunk...
你们早就知道  却不跟我们说
You guys knew about this and didn't tell us?
他走桃花运  我们却要挨打
He has sex and we get hit in our heads!
我要你马上离开  滚出去  马上滚
You know what, I want you to leave! Get outta here! Just get out! Now!
不  不要
No!! No!!
我要留下来  好好谈这件事
I wanna stay. I wanna talk about this.
好  她怎么样
Okay! All right. How was she?
-什么  -她功夫很厉害吗
- What? - Was she good?
不要回答
Don't answer that.
说啊  罗斯  你说你想谈
Come on, Ross, you said you wanted to talk about it.
那我们就来谈  她怎么样
Let's talk about it. How was she?
-她...  -很逊  糟透了
- She was.... - Awful. Horrible!
-不怎么样  -跟你没得比
- She was not good. Not good. - She was nothing compared to you.
她不一样
She was different.
不一样的好吗
Good different?
没有人喜欢改变
Nobody likes change.
-够了  -干吗  好了好了好了
- Just stop! - What? Okay! Okay! Okay!
我们该做些什么吗
Should we do something?
对  永远不要背着瑞秋偷腥
Yeah. Never cheat on Rachel.
对不起  好吗
I'm sorry, okay?
我很抱歉  我当时也觉得自己恶心
I'm sorry. I was disgusted with myself...
今天早上  我很难过
and this morning I was so, I was so upset
然后收到你的留言  我好高兴
and then I got your message and I was so happy.
我一心只想
And all I wanted was to
尽快把她赶出我的公寓
get her out of my apartment as fast as possible.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你的小女朋友是几点离开的
What time did your little friend leave?
我的天  她在场  她那时还在你家
Oh, my God. She was there? She was still there?
我在你家的时候  她也在场
She was in there when I was in there?
听我说  重点是她对我毫无意义
Listen, the important thing is she meant nothing to me.
却值得你为她破坏我们的关系
And yet she was worth jeopardizing our relationship!
那时候我不知道我们还有关系
I didn't think there was a relationship to jeopardise.
我以为我们分手了
I thought we were broken up.
只是暂时分开一下
We were on a break.
对我来说  那可能是一辈子
That, for all I knew would, could last forever.
对于我来说那就是分手
That to me is a breakup.
你想通过揪字眼来推卸责任吗
You think you're gonna get out of this on a technicality?
听着  我没有推卸责任
Look, I'm not trying to get out of anything, okay.
我以为我们的关系完了
I thought our relationship was dead.
所以你马上就去享艳福了
Well, you sure had a hell of a time at the wake.
我想我们不该再听下去了
Y'know what, I don't think we should listen to this anymore.
你干嘛  我们不能出去
What are you doing? We can't go out there.
为什么不行  我饿了
Why not? I'm hungry.
因为他们会知道我们在偷听
Because they'll know we've been listening.
老天  我还得从甘瑟那里听到这件事
God! And I have to hear about it from Gunther!
拜托  好像我很期待让他告诉你似的
Come on! Like I wanted him to tell you,
我到处奔波  就是不想让你知道
I ran all over the place trying to make sure that didn't happen!
你好体贴
Oh, that is so sweet.
我想我又重新爱上你了
I think I'm falling in love with you all over again.
我觉得我们可以出去
Y'know what, I think we can go out there.
他们有其它更重要的事要担心
I mean they have more important things to worry about.
对啊  不会有事的
Yeah, we'll be fine.
瑞秋  我本来想告诉你的
Rachel, I wanted to tell you.
我觉得我应该告诉你  真的
I thought I should. I did.
但是钱德勒和乔伊叫我不要说
And then Chandler and Joey convinced me not to!
把门用腊条封起来  我们再也不走了
Wax the door shut. We're never leaving.
喂  我是菲比
Hi, it's Phoebe.
请人帮我代班  李哈克先生九点的预约
Listen someone's gonna have to take my 9:00 with Mr. Rehack,
因为现在已经九点一刻  我人还没到
'cause it's like 9:15 now, and I'm not there.
你不觉得  如果当时我没误会
Don't you realise none of this would've ever happened if
你和马克上床  这事就根本不会发生吗
I didn't think at that same moment you were having sex with Mark?
好吧
All right.
就说我跟马克上了床
Let's say I had slept with Mark.
你觉得可以原谅我吗
Would you have been able to forgive me?
我会的
Yes, I would.
你不介意马克吻我
You'd be okay if you knew that Mark had kissed me,
跟我裸体相见  跟我做爱
and been naked with me and made love to me?
对
Yes.
你知道我俩欲火焚身  汗湿翻滚的身体
You knew that our hot, sweaty, writhing bodies were...
好吧  对  我会伤心欲绝
Okay, okay, yeah, I would have been devastated...
不过我还是想跟你在一起
but I would still want to be with you.
因为  是你啊
Because, I mean, it's you.
怎么样
What?
拜托  瑞秋  告诉我你在想什么
Come on, Rachel, tell me what you're thinking.
我想
I'm thinking...
叫一个披萨
I'm gonna order a pizza.
叫一个披萨  意思是
Order a pizza, like...
我原谅你
"I forgive you"?
老天
Oh, man!
披萨
Pizza?
我喜欢吃披萨
I like pizza.
披萨上面放上橄榄
Put olives on the pizza.
我们可以吃脱毛膏  那是有机的
We could eat the wax! It's organic!
太好了  连毛一起吃下去
Oh, great. Food with hair on it.
不  我不是说用过的
No, not the used wax.
因为那样会很神经
Because that would be crazy?
可以算我一份吗  因为我也饿了
Could I get in on that? Because I'm kind of hungry myself.
好
Fine.
我想要一份大号的披萨
Yes, I'd like to order a large pizza.
-别放凤尾鱼  -多加一份凤尾鱼
- No anchovies. - With extra anchovies.
没关系  我挑掉就好了
That's okay. I'll pick them off.
麻烦把凤尾鱼剁碎了  搅到酱汁里好吗
Yeah, and could you please chop some up and put it right in the sauce?
你想吃的话  最后一块给你
You can have the last piece if you want.
应该的  你跟别人上床了
Well, I should think so. You slept with someone.
他们应该会和好吧
They're gonna get through this, aren't they?
当然啦  他们是罗斯跟瑞秋
Yeah. Come on, it's Ross and Rachel.
他们非和好不可
They've got to.
万一他们不能和好呢
What if they don't?
你们觉得我需要新的走路姿势吗
You think I need a new walk?
什么
What?
我从高中开始  走路的姿势都一样
Well, I've been walking the same way since high school.
你知道有些人一踏进房间
You know how some guys walk into a room
就吸引所有人的目光
and everybody takes notice?
我想我需要这种万众瞩目的走路姿势
I think I need a take-notice walk.
你说这些话过大脑了吗
Are you actually saying these words?
你现在连话都不跟我说了吗
What, now you're not even talking to me?
听我说  瑞秋  对不起
Look, Rachel, I'm sorry. Ok?
我很抱歉  我当时疯了
I'm sorry. I was out of my mind.
我以为我会失去你  我不知道如何是好
I thought I'd lost you. I didn't know what to do. Come on!
不是疯到一定程度我绝不会做这种事
Come on, how insane must I have been to do something like this?
我从不偷情  不是吗
I don't cheat, right?
我不是这种人  我不是乔伊
That's not me. I'm not Joey!
好吧  算了
Yeah, okay.
凌晨三点了
It's three in the morning.
他们都没意识到我已经回家了
They don't know that I've come home yet.
他俩谁都没奇怪我到哪里去了
You notice how neither one of them aren't wondering where I am?
人有时候就是只想到自己
You know, people can be so self-involved.
你知道吗
You know what? You know what?
不是我要分开一下的
I'm not the one that wanted that break.
是你放弃我们的  是你
You're the one that bailed on us. You're the one
在事情稍有不顺的时候  就调头逃跑
that ran the moment when things got just a little rough.
-那  -那怎么样
- That's... - That's what?
-这根本不是重点  -现在我们
- That is neither here nor there. - Okay, well here we are.
又到了进退两难的时刻  瑞秋
Now we're in a tough spot again, Rach.
你打算怎么办  你要怎么办
What do you wanna do? How do you want to handle it?
是努力解决问题  还是放弃
Do you wanna fight for us? Or, do you wanna bail?
听着  我
Look, I,
我做了一件很过分
I did a terrible,
很蠢很蠢的事  好吗
stupid, stupid thing, okay?
对不起  我希望能收回这个错误
I'm sorry. I wish I could take it back,
但不可能
but I can't.
我只是不能眼睁睁看着彼此放弃
I just can't see us throwing away
明知道很美好的感情
something we know is so damn good.
瑞秋  我好爱你
Rachel, I love you so much.
不要  罗斯  不要
No, Ross! Don't!
你不能吻我两下  就让整件事烟消云散
You can't just kiss me and think you're gonna make it all go away.
事情不是这样的  这样没有用的  明白吗
It doesn't work that way. It doesn't just make it better. Okay?
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
我觉得你应该离开
I think you should go.
什么
What?
我真的觉得你该走了
I really think you need to go now.
好吧
Okay, okay.
今天早上你还说我们同心协力
This morning you said there was nothing so big
没有过不去的难关
that we couldn't work past it together.
我那时候知道什么
What the hell did I know?
我们一定有办法度过这一关  好吗
Look, look, there's got to be a way we can work past this. Okay.
我不能想像没有你的日子
I can't imagine, I can't imagine my life without you.
知道吗  没有...
You know. Without,
没有这双手臂
without these arms,
你的面容和你的心
and your face, and this heart.
你善良的心  瑞秋
your good heart, Rach, and....
不  我办不到
No. I can't,
你在我眼里完全变了
you're a totally different person to me now.
我以前总觉得  你永远永远
I used to think of you as somebody
不会伤害我
that would never, ever hurt me.
永远不会
Ever.
天哪  现在我满脑子都是你跟她的画面
God, and now I just can't stop picturing you with her.
我做不到  你说什么
I can't. It doesn't matter what you say
做什么都没用  罗斯
or what you do, Ross.
一切都不能回头了
It's just changed, everything.
永远不能
Forever.
不可能会这样
Yeah, but this can't be it, I mean.
那为什么会这样呢
Then how come it is?
他们好久没动静了
They've been quiet for a long time.
也许她把他杀了
Maybe she killed him.
我们走吧
Let's go.
这是你新的走路姿势吗
Is that your new walk?
不是  我快尿出来了
No. I really have to pee.